WHEN LIFE GIVES YOU TANGERINES
Let's just not have the baby.
What if Ae-sun dies during childbirth?
We shouldn't let her do that!
Just wait until the baby is born.
You'll be even more annoying.
Remember, you have to
support her head like this.
Uh, no.
I don't think I want to.
I shouldn't.
I think I'll hurt her.
You just have to be careful.
Honey?
The baby. She's a bit…
A bit strange looking?
She's all wrinkly, huh?
Look at her nostrils.
We can fit a cotton swab in there.
She's just so… little.
So little.
How will she make it in this world?
A dog could run in and snatch her up.
What are you so worried about? What?
You're the Steelheart.
We'll be there to protect her.
She'll always have us.
Oh, she smiled!
All those years ago,
my parents couldn't have known…
What?
…just how long I'd be in their debt.
Who are you anyway?
This isn't like you at all.
You hate it when I pack things up for you.
Should I not take the tangerines
just because you want them?
Your husband, has he lost his job?
Of course not. Why would you think that?
When you're pinching pennies,
fruit is always the first thing to go.
Fine, I won't take them.
Why can't we visit your new place?
We still haven't seen it.
Just come. It's fine.
I'll come tomorrow, then.
You have so much luggage to carry.
Actually, uh, tomorrow's not great.
I'm busy.
Well, busy or not, I'm coming over.
What's the rush?
What's wrong?
You can't fool me.
How you're acting right now
is just like Eun-myeong.
When he asked me not to visit his school,
there was a reason.
Tomorrow, I wanna see
what it is for myself.
We don't have room for you.
There's no room for you to come over.
Why not?
Uh, it's a one-bedroom.
I quit my job.
I started a business,
and I put up everything.
I'm all in.
Oh, Mother, who knew
Geum-myeong could get reckless?
Maybe Eun-myeong is passing
his baton to his sister.
Wait, what? But why?
Why did you quit your job?
What happened to your hand?
What happened? What?
Everyone get out! Get out!
If none of you are going to listen to me,
then just get out!
But I'm injured.
I told you a hundred times
about that uncle in Hallim
who had to have his fingers amputated
because of frostbite.
"Wear gloves.
Wear gloves when you're handling ice."
I was like a broken record!
You never listen, do you?
Your uncle Jong-gu
always has new business ideas,
and he has to ask me for money
just to survive.
Mom, do you even care
what kind of business it is?
I've never been the one
to cause problems for this family, have I?
- I can hear you.
- Now, for the first time in my life…
What about kids? Are you not having kids?
I knew
you were gonna say that again.
You think you're fine
because you're still young.
But when you get older
and start getting sick,
what will you do without--
What, Mom? Did you have kids
just so you can have a nurse?
Hyeon-suk already has two children!
And what future do they have?
I can still hear you.
You think kids just grow up
all up on their own?
Do you have any idea what a kid costs now?
You think only rich people raise children?
I don't.
I just don't want to have children
I can't provide for.
I want to buy them
new clothes every season.
I want to buy them shoes
that actually fit.
I want to pay for piano lessons,
for ballet, their first studio apartment!
I don't have money, and I had kids.
Look, Hyeon-suk's family
bought all this stuff, didn't they?
Che-il has one grandpa
with money at least!
Did you come here
to pick a fight?
Rolling around
at rock bottom is draining.
Everything's just
really difficult right now.
Their son had frostbite,
and their daughter had downsized
to a studio apartment.
But in the end…
Our troubles
are never going to end.
Will they?
What's happening?
Where did we go wrong?
…it was those words from my poor mother…
Oh God!
…that made my father take a risk.
Goddammit.
I'm sick of this.
The first risk
my dad ever took…
was launched from a bazooka.
I hear your daughter
is also starting a business.
She needs a backup somewhere.
Do it for your family.
That's it! You've lost your mind!
How could you do something so reckless?
Any idiot can tell
something's fishy about this.
The moment I heard you sold
the cabbage field, I got suspicious.
Some company chairman
is building a vacation home.
You want us to believe
the money just fell into your lap one day?
- Not buying it.
- What the hell's out here anyway?
Who on earth runs a store
in the middle of nowhere?
Great, if there are no people to feed,
there's always the wild dogs.
I heard a golf course is being built here.
Golf course?
Well, isn't that lucky for you.
What a coincidence.
Haven't you seen
those investigation shows?
When people are scamming you,
everything they say
sounds too good to be true.
You wanna be homeless
at your age?
Who puts up their house
to buy a commercial building at 50?
If he can't do it at 50,
he'll never do it at all.
If he wants to take a risk,
better late than never.
I'm proud of you.
Even if we show up
and the building turns out to be haunted,
even if there's no building there at all,
we're sticking this out together,
Gwan-Sik.
The loyalty between these two…
It's certainly something to behold,
all right.
My head.
Tell him to pull over and let me out.
Look at all these banners.
Which is it?
Huh?
Oh my.
Wait a minute.
What are all these buildings
doing way out here?
Oh my. A hospital, a clinic,
a supermarket, and a specialty restaurant.
PREMIUM COMMERCIAL PROPERTY
WITH EVERYTHING
RENTAL INQUIRY FOR COMMERCIAL PROPERTY
If they ever build that golf course,
even Park Se-ri might come in here.
Well, if she does,
meeting her will be one more thing
you can thank your son for.
By the way,
you both own this place, right?
It's good to know
my family name is on something.
Are you still angry
over these old issues?
Is this about the boat we had?
'Cause I said
it belonged to the Oh family?
Whoever bought it, it was nice
to see him riding in that boat.
You can guess how it felt
when I heard my son had gone
from a captain to a manual laborer.
I know you've been married to him
practically for your entire life,
but he's the only son I have.
Seeing him suffer
just breaks my heart to pieces.
I'm sorry, Mother.
I took your precious son away from you,
and he's suffered ever since.
Well, there's no need to be sorry. Uh…
Tell me, I'm curious.
Do you remember everything from the past?
Everything about your son,
like the way he always chose me over you.
I mean…
Oh, you know.
That time when I slapped you.
It only happened once.
You're not still upset about that,
are you?
How could I ever forget such a thing?
That was the very first
I had ever been slapped by anybody.
It's okay.
You made up for it.
How did I do that?
I've never done a thing for you.
It was when we
lost Dong-myeong.
You never once blamed me, and you…
you didn't criticize me either
for any of it.
When a cow's lost its calf,
you don't put a yolk on it.
I went to your house early in the mornings
just to check up on you.
I still have that golden toad,
the one you stole when you ran away.
I'll give it to you instead of Gyeong-ok.
I'm sorry I was so hard on you.
Consider it a thank-you present
for moving on.
I guess my mother-in-law
is a cut above your mother-in-law.
Way above.
COMMERCIAL LEASE AGREEMENT
LESSEE NAME: PARK YEONG-RAN
Meanwhile,
there was someone else firing a bazooka.
Jesus.
You been going crazy
with the sweets lately?
What are you gonna do
about all that weight?
People go into business
with pretty realtors, not fatties.
See these bikes here?
We'll get rid of that belly in no time.
Plus, I've heard
when couples do things together,
it tends to strengthen the relationship.
Did ping-pong strengthen
your relationship with that woman?
I told you it was a mixed league, okay?
It's actually very common.
Is that why you chose
Mi-suk for real estate?
Fine, th… then don't ride the bike.
I'm doing a nice thing for you.
Fine.
I'll try it.
We'll take a ride around the block.
Woo-hoo!
Oh!
Yeah.
Look! I still got it! See?
Check me out!
See?
Whoo!
Figures.
He won't ride next to me. He never has.
Hey! Hurry up!
This is a cycling course.
You understand what cycling means?
Go fast!
Hey, look. Go up ahead.
The view here is just…
I mean, wow! Oh!
Where do you think you're going?
Huh?
- Whoa!
- Go away.
Where do you think you're going?
You can't just ride past me like that.
Shit, uh…
Wow! I wonder why she ran out to see you.
Huh? Who's that?
Hmm. I see you found a new playmate.
Look, babe,
go back inside and make your jeon.
Hmm.
Why'd you agree to a bike ride
in the first place?
Was that your way of saying goodbye?
Well, I suppose I did it
because, after 30 years of marriage,
we'd never been around
the neighborhood together once.
Is this because of Mom's tangerine field?
Are you selling it
to start a real estate business?
Exactly. I don't need your money
to eat anymore.
You just have to ruin everything,
don't you?
After all the effort
I put in to make it work, you just--
Am I a dog?
Do you think after all these years
of keeping me cooped up at home
while you had fun all around town,
one bike ride would fix it?
How dare you!
When the kids come back,
tell them to pick up
the rest of their shoes.
Or else I can throw them away.
I don't know why
they left all these pairs behind.
Okay, okay.
All right, I see what you're doing.
I see it.
Don't put on a show.
Well, it's not a show.
And you know that, Sang-gil.
I put food on the table for this family,
and this is what I get?
A runaway for a daughter.
Now, I have to take time out of
my crazy schedule to go hunt you down.
Did you put back my bedroom door?
I need my privacy!
Good Lord. How the hell did I end up
with a kid like you anyway?
Before you, we never had
a troublemaker in the family.
Oh-seong, if you beat up Eun-myeong
one more time,
I'm taking you all to court!
- You goddamn brat!
- Knock it off!
So proud of my whole family today!
SANG-GIL LOVES OK
Do you really like this boy that much?
Dear, this is your first love, isn't it?
"First love"? Who cares?
Don't encourage her now!
Can you please act like a mother?
At least you get to experience it.
I never did.
So you really never loved me?
Not even for a little while?
If I had loved you,
I would've lost my mind long ago.
Remember,
after I gave birth to Hyeon-suk, you were
seeing that woman from the bathhouse.
We used to be in the same class at school.
That's all.
I thought you went to school in Seoul.
How dare you.
When I found out about the affair,
I raised hell.
You threw a clothes hanger at me.
I didn't throw it at you.
You ran at me and bumped into it.
Since then,
I've had no tears left to cry.
When a woman's heart is
beaten down enough, she stops feeling.
People tell me I'm a saint, but I'm not.
Not loving you was
the only way I survived.
- Honey.
- Don't even try.
- Save your breath.
You know, Hyeon-suk has asthma
because you always smoked in front of her.
When I listened to you refuse her
the money she needed to save her husband,
any sentiment I had left for you
disappeared from my heart forever.
Oh shit.
Do I really have to do this?
Do you know how humiliating this is?
I would say your life has been
pretty good so far.
All I want now is
the chance to enjoy the rest of mine.
Please just let me go.
After all,
I did my best to raise your children.
JEJU DISTRICT COURT
Goddammit.
We don't have to change cars right now.
How come you never told me
you recognized my shoe that day?
Why does that matter now?
That woman's fleeing
with her child.
Look, they're like refugees from the war,
aren't they?
Get a picture of that woman!
Get a picture of her now!
How dare she.
She's been out dancing?
If I had busted you for dancing,
you would have left right then and there.
You would've raised hell
and left me on the spot.
I'm not even smiling.
You were always so cold to me.
I nearly froze to death.
What do you want, punk?
I don't have any money to give you.
Jesus.
My wife thought you'd need that.
She was right.
INSTANT RICE
Goddammit.
She did dodge the bullet.
Out of my way!
Why you little… How dare you!
Why don't you come to your senses first,
Bu Sang-gil?
You hear me?
And then we'll find out
who dodged whose bullet!
How dare you!
Why is it so surprising
when, one day, we reap
what we've so relentlessly sown?
GEUMEUNDONG'S
If this goes south,
we're losing our apartment.
Not in a thousand years would I ever dream
you'd throw me a curveball like this.
So then why didn't you try
to talk me out of it?
Well,
…when you first told me
that you wanted to buy this store,
I realized it's been 30 years
since I saw that look on your face.
So if you're scared, Gwan-sik,
walk away now.
Just go back home.
In all… 19 years of my life, Ae-sun…
I've never felt more excited.
You haven't been so excited in 30 years.
How can I ruin that?
Still, I don't know what made you try
something you've never done before.
Was it Geum-myeong's business?
Or maybe Eun-myeong's hand?
I realized if I never tried,
I would be proving what you said about me.
Listen, living with you, that would be
too much of a gamble for me.
I wanted our life to be halfway decent.
Just never seems to work out.
I feel like it's my fault
that our kids are struggling.
I hate that.
It's not true what people say.
They say money isn't everything.
But we all know it is.
We even need money
to do something for our grandkids.
Che-il gets pajamas from Sang-gil,
and they're always better quality pajamas
than anything I could get him. Always!
Listen, if I could go back 30 years,
I would choose to run away with you again.
If I hadn't gone with you,
I wouldn't be a restaurant owner today.
Unbelievable, right?
That's our restaurant.
You really that excited?
Stop acting like a couple of teenagers
and get in here.
Is she gonna come here every day?
She said she'd work the counter.
She did?
Can you call and ask
when they're installing the toilet?
I told you, construction isn't over yet.
What on earth did they stop for?
When are the rest of the stores moving in?
What we didn't count on
was an unexpected setback.
Can't you see the realtor
just dumped this on you and ran away?
Why'd you even do this anyway?
You hate get-rich-quick schemes.
Even Steelheart
had entered a season
when his child was reprimanding him.
It would've been better
if you did nothing at all, Dad!
You traded a valuable plot of land
for this trash!
You said you'd never sell
the cabbage field, right?
Why did you do it?
What about the cabbage field?
It's not a vacation house, after all.
They're building a hotel there.
But they're building a golf course here.
And a hospital.
It's all a lie. All of it.
The realtor said that
to swindle my father!
Look, Dad,
the way things look to me,
you're the unluckiest guy in the world.
Do you realize that?
Then what happens to us?
Are they taking the apartment away?
Couldn't we pay off the interest
and list this place for sale?
Who would buy it? And how would we pay?
You wanna ask a loan shark for the money?
All right, then.
On Monday, I'll go to the bank.
- I'll mention I'm the owner of--
- Please!
You know how the world works, don't you?
Banks never gamble on people like us!
If you don't know any better,
ask your children for advice!
If you had kept that cabbage field,
we could've sent Che-il to study abroad!
It's your father's money, understand?
It's not yours. It's your father's.
You have no right
to raise your voice at him,
even if he was robbed.
You know why he did this?
Because you were always going,
"Money, money, money!"
You were always pressuring him for more,
so he did this to get it for you.
When your scheme landed you in jail,
did you discuss your plans with us?
"If you don't know any better,
ask your children for advice."
"It would be better if you did nothing."
How dare you say that to him!
How dare you, Eun-myeong!
He's done everything for you.
You won't disrespect your father's life.
He's never lived it for himself.
Let's go home.
I got your cash.
Goal accomplished.
g.o.d.'s Babysitting Diaries.
For Jae-min to become
a healthier and smarter child,
the big brothers of g.o.d.
visit a playroom with him.
There's a lot for him to play with.
Let's find out just how much smarter
Jae-min has become.
Who asked you to get us money?
Where'd you get it from?
You didn't have that many other options.
- Tell me where you got it.
- I borrowed it.
And I dipped into my savings, Mom.
I felt humiliated asking people,
but I still did it.
I guess you know you should be ashamed
to come to us for money.
Why did you even come?
Who told you to go around
asking for money? Why did you do that?
You shouldn't have.
How could I not?
I'm the eldest sibling, the eldest child.
The pillar of this family.
Isn't that what you raised me to be?
We never…
We never meant for you to--
It's what I felt growing up,
even if it's not what you intended.
Ever since I first started working,
I sent you guys
a hundred thousand won each month.
You think I wanted to send it?
I earned that money.
Of course I wanted to keep it.
We never asked for it.
I was always telling you
not to send it to us.
You know why I sent that money?
It wasn't because I was overwhelmed
with gratitude for you guys.
It's because I felt guilty
for not wanting to send it.
Spending it on myself felt so wrong.
That's what family is to me.
It's about feeling guilty over everything.
Do you know what that feels like?
Be quiet. Your father will hear it.
If I'm this family's goddamn pillar,
why'd you send me overseas?
Did you do all these things
just to kill me with guilt?
I know that you guys
barely make ends meet because of me.
All these years, you put your hopes in me
and suffered for it.
Do you know what a burden that was?
I'm sick of being the big fish
that made it out of the little pond!
The pillar, the older sibling!
God, I'm sick of it all!
Yang Geum-myeong!
For the first time in my life,
Dad raised his voice to me.
"Yang Geum-myeong."
That's all he said.
But it stung me badly.
It felt like he had told me
I'd never amount to anything.
Goddamn brat.
She's so arrogant. So arrogant.
She loses her famous temper
and just leaves.
Well, what about me? What about me?
I've been putting up with her damn temper
ever since she was a teenager.
She has no idea
I'm going through menopause. Jeez.
But I get how she feels.
Being the eldest was a burden for me too.
And now she's going through that.
By the time you were her age,
you were already raising two children
and had buried a third in your heart,
and all that while street vending.
No one can do it like you.
No one.
That stubborn girl.
She should've taken these anyway.
She might be stubborn,
but she's not heartless.
You know she's on that bus
crying her eyes out.
How could I have known then
that at my mom's funeral,
this day would be the first thing
that I'd remember?
Don't peel any more quail eggs for her.
She doesn't seem to care anyway.
Let's stop and rest.
You said you were having hot flashes.
Oh, I'm so upset for some reason.
I don't know if it's hormones or what.
I just wanna break everything.
Oh my God.
Oh my! Look!
What, what? What now?
Oh my God.
Oh my God!
MY HORMONES ARE ALL OVER THE PLACE TOO
SORRY, GOMEN, MIAN…
It was
hormones versus hormones,
and Mom was defeated yet again.
Why didn't she take the food?
Why didn't she?
That's why she's been
asking around for money.
She got pregnant, just like me.
She feels hopeless too.
Oh God.
Dad's world
was once only seven pounds.
Oh, hi.
Now,
she would have one of her own.
Chung-seob, I can't do this.
Oh, I can't do this anymore.
Honey?
How bad is it?
Should I call for the doctor?
Should I ask your mom to come?
Can you ask the nurses again?
Can you ask them to give me the epidural?
Okay.
Oh, you're here.
- Can she have the epidural?
- We cannot give her any more.
Why not?
You're not dilating fast enough.
The doctor ordered to stop the epidural.
Wait, wait, hold on.
That doesn't make any sense?
She's had contractions the past 12 hours.
My… my wife is very weak.
The real problem
is that… the baby won't move.
Mr. Park, you need to sign a waiver form.
- In the event the mother and child…
- My wife.
Save her.
No matter what, save her.
Wait, but why?
Why isn't it moving?
Hello, Mother. Hi.
The thing is, I'm not sure
what's going on right now.
She's fully dilated,
but the baby doesn't wanna come out.
They say it's obstructed labor.
Honestly…
they're not doing well.
Uh… uh, what's the problem? What's wrong?
Uh, is… is… is she in danger?
Is something wrong?
Mother, I'm sorry to ask,
but could you come over?
Geum-myeong's asking for you.
She's asking for her mom.
Sweetie, what is it? What's wrong?
As the young branch
was developing a new shoot…
Hang on.
…the whole tree shook with fear
and grew tense.
One, two, three.
No, not yet, not yet.
Now push. Push, push, push.
One, two, three, four.
No, don't stop now.
That would be very bad.
But it hurts so much.
Okay, breathe, breathe.
Push, push, push, push.
One, two, three, four.
- Come on, you have to push.
- I think I'm about to pass out.
Again, one, two, three.
Keep breathing. Don't stop.
I need you to push a little more.
Push, push, push.
One, two. Don't stop now. Don't stop!
Come on. Wake up. Wake up!
Oh no, no, no, no.
Mom, you can't give up now.
Mom, Mom, don't stop now.
Your baby is in danger.
She's stuck at the shoulders.
Mom, don't you wanna see your baby?
Don't you wanna see your baby?
Geum-myeong,
you follow your grandma, okay?
Go to her place and get something to eat.
I'll see you soon, okay, dear?
It's all right. It's all right.
Don't worry, cutie, okay? Okay?
She's alive.
Hurry, get the baby to cry.
We made two resolutions.
The first was to treat Mom well,
and the second…
We're not having another one.
We're not. We're not having another one.
Stop making me laugh.
The government has paid off
the emergency funds
loaned to it by the IMF,
and Korea is now
back in control of its economy.
Due to the risk of a national…
I guess Sae-bom is
a financial crisis baby, isn't she, huh?
You and I met inside the theater
at the start of the crisis,
and she was born on the day that it ended.
Really. Some coincidence, huh?
Right?
What is it? Should I call the doctor?
Are you in pain? What's wrong?
I just…
I just can't believe it really happened.
I mean, how?
I know. They made you suffer for 28 hours.
It's outrageous!
That much pain would kill a cow!
Yeah, but how did my mom have me
when she was 18 years old?
She was only a child.
In the blink of an eye,
my mom had become a mother-in-law
and a grandma.
Our lives had gone through
so many changes so quickly,
it was overwhelming.
When I think of how
her own mother had already passed,
of how there was no epidural.
Just think of what she had gone through.
And that's not it.
When my brother was born,
she had to ride in a rickety carriage.
Honey!
Mom.
Mommy's here.
Oh, Mom.
Good job, honey.
Their little baby
now had a baby of her own.
So proud.
The moment
they stepped into that room,
they became my fortress,
and I was their little girl once again.
Uh, hi, Father.
Uh… you know, Father, I sometimes think
that it feels like I married
the princess of Tangerine Island.
Is that a complaint?
Sae-bom is well.
Take this. It's seaweed soup
with sea urchins. Real ones.
The aunties harvested them.
I'm curious.
Who do you think Sae-bom looks like?
My mom and her sisters
all think she has Geum-myeong's nose.
She has her nose, eh?
- She does?
- Oh, you haven't seen her?
- I'm sure they'd let you…
- We will. Don't worry.
Did you assume we'd go
to your daughter before our own?
I mean the world to my parents.
- Just keep that in mind going forward.
- Okay.
What did the doctor say?
She's all right, isn't she?
Yes, she's a big girl.
Already eight pounds.
They X-rayed her shoulders,
and everything's fine.
Not her. I meant Geum-myeong.
Is her gestational diabetes
over now that she's given birth?
Oh, yes.
I assure you,
your daughter is perfectly healthy.
Are you trying to pick a fight with me,
or does it just feel that way?
Every time
I visited my parents, they had chicken
and gave me the drumsticks.
I was always their number one.
Oh, you already
bought baby clothes?
They're all the best quality.
Dad didn't even look at the price.
He just asked for the most expensive ones.
Wha-- Why does a newborn
need expensive clothes?
Your dad
has a new dream for himself.
To be the rich grandpa for once.
Jesus, I didn't mean that, Dad.
Why do you have to take everything I say
to heart?
Here.
Why don't we go see
if Sae-bom has her nose or not?
With Sae-bom's birth,
springtime had arrived yet again.
REALTOR HAN MAN-CHEOL!
YOUR FAMILY WILL BE CURSED!
WHY ABANDON THESE BUILDINGS?
OWN UP TO PEOPLE'S MONEY!
JEJU'S JANUARY DAYTIME TEMPERATURE
REACHES 21.4 DEGREES CELSIUS
And, like so many times before,
my parents survived
yet another winter together.
You really wanna run this restaurant?
You think people will like it?
They'll just have to take
a five-minute detour.
They can sit down, eat quickly, and go.
We'll give them plenty
to justify the trip.
But will they take that trip?
Hell, if they don't come to us…
we'll take it to them.
You wanna do delivery?
Jjajangmyeon can be delivered, but squids…
I caught squids for over 30 years.
There's nothing you can't do with squids.
They don't know anything out here.
Here, they overcharge you
for a dead squid.
We're going to give them
the freshest squids you can get.
It'll be the tastiest and the cheapest
and will be delivered the fastest.
It's a no-brainer.
And besides,
we've worked hard before.
We can work hard again.
My love,
you know me.
You know, if we do this,
I'll give it my all.
I know you will.
We'll do this the only way we know how.
And so,
they resolved to do what they did best.
It was the same mentality that once
helped Mom plow that stony field
and Dad sail into the deepest seas.
Hello.
GEUMEUNDONG'S
WE AIM TO GET IT DONE IN 10 MINUTES!
The heavens
must have taken pity on us
because, like
the Korean national soccer team,
we kept getting corner kicks.
Soccer games meant deliveries.
- And soon, it was 2002.
- He shoots, he scores!
Park Ji-sung! He scores!
Park Ji-sung!
- South Korea is ahead of Portugal!
- Did we score?
- Incredible!
- One to zero!
Hey, Gwan-sik!
I told you Park Ji-sung would score!
Park Ji-sung!
I've been waiting 20 years for this!
Hey, hey, hey. What is that?
Bring me a box of raw squid! A whole box!
Oh, oh, oh! Yeah!
Daehanminguk!
Their business tactics
would be similar.
Dad would be Park Ji-sung,
and Mom would be Coach Hiddink.
Let's be honest here.
No one in Jeju knows squid
better than we do.
Certainly not those mainland amateurs.
They may run your restaurants,
but they're phoning it in.
You know they'll all fail.
They think squids are nothing
but side dishes!
It's an afterthought. Take it or leave it.
But for us, squid is the star!
To us, the squid is Ahn Jung-hwan.
Oh boy.
- So that's Gwan-sik's wife?
- Uh-huh.
How about it, Captain?
Give us an exclusive.
It's an easy call.
So what about it?
You haven't mentioned
how much you're willing to pay.
Well, we can't pay you too much right now.
Yeesh.
Soon, you'll be asking us
to take your squids,
but it'll be too late.
It's now or never.
She's a stubborn one, isn't she?
You think she gets her way with Gwan-sik?
Do you have to ask? It's obvious.
And why am I having this conversation
with you instead of Gwan-sik?
That's how it's always been.
The women call the shots in that family.
GEUMEUNDONG'S
CEO, OH AE-SUN
I need a yes or a no.
Don't give me a maybe.
The decision
to buy Samsung stocks
worth 300 won or three million…
that is entirely up to you.
To be honest, sir,
I'm meeting with
two more people after you.
I'm ready to make you an industry leader,
but if you choose
not to go on this journey together,
I'll have to find
the next diamond in the rough.
This may be your last chance.
Well…
It goes to show
how much I believe in this idea.
This won't just change the industry.
It'll redefine it.
And what's the story
with your company's name?
Ah, it comes from my mother.
Growing up, this was always her motto.
"Domestic duty-free stores
to open in Jeju."
Does that mean Koreans
can buy cigarettes tax-free there?
- That a question for your father-in-law?
- Honey.
My friends keep asking me
to buy them a big bundle of cigarettes
every time I go to Seoul.
I guess they think that you can buy
anything at the duty-free store.
Your friends are morons.
I never thought something
the government did would actually help us.
If we get more tourists,
people are going to order our food
from the resorts up the mountain.
Has that film crew
not called us from their motel?
Are they ordering from somewhere else?
Oh yeah.
What are they filming in Jeju anyway?
It's for a film starring… What's his name?
The guy with the nice teeth. Um…
Oh, Lee Byung-hun. Lee Byung-hun.
Ah, Lee Byung-hun.
UNLIMITED REFILLS OF SQUID SOUP
FOR DINE-IN CUSTOMERS
The free kicks didn't stop.
Yes.
If you dine in
instead of ordering delivery,
you'll be given a 10% discount.
Yes.
That's right, 10%.
Hello. Welcome!
This must be Byun-sama's
favorite spot. Look, his autograph.
Oh, so is his picture.
Jeez, another pair of arigatous.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute, please.
I wonder where he sat.
- Right here.
- Right here?
Oh, Mother?
They're selling restaurant chairs
on Joonggonara. Should we get some?
Wait. Here you go.
You think we need them?
That was when
Joonggonara was brand new.
Hey!
Get the family together!
What?
We're family all of a sudden?
You were supposed to be watching the kids.
Thanks to Joonggonara,
we heard a name we'd given up on.
Cheol-yong.
Cheol-yong, I said!
Park Cheol-yong's arrested by the cops!
Oh my God!
They found the buncheong stoneware!
I guess nobody wanted
to pay him the 70 million.
He couldn't get rid of it,
so that moron
put the whole set up online for sale.
So then, um, we're keeping the stoneware?
Huh.
Yes?
Who's speaking?
Direct penalty kick.
Come again?
It was yet another season
when past kindness begat another kindness.
She's as pure as a white dove.
Mmm. This taste
is what I come to Jeju for.
The squid soup here
is my ultimate comfort food.
You could say
it saved my life.
- Is she a regular?
- Never seen her.
Uh, Miss Jeong, um,
could you say that famous phrase?
Excuse me. We agreed
you wouldn't make her say that.
Just one shot of her saying it.
It's all right. I'll give it a shot.
"Squid soup for sale. Soup!"
How was that?
Just like in the movie!
SOUP FOR SALE, SOUP!
GEUMEUNDONG'S SQUID SOUP
I CAN VOUCH FOR THIS PLACE
JEONG MI-IN
You must really love squid.
I've never seen you eat like that before.
- I don't eat seafood.
- What?
Go have a smoke and get directions
to our next location.
Fine.
Miss Jeong, you know you can trust me,
so be honest with me here.
I don't care if you went to Macau,
and you got your face done.
I need you to always tell me the truth.
Is it… something to do with that man?
There's nothing between you,
is there? Hmm?
- Hey.
- Is there?
Would I be here if there were nothing?
Don't do this to me, Miss Jeong.
I have to send child support in dollars.
That man is the reason
you can pay your bills.
He's the only reason
that Rolex is on your wrist right now.
When the scandal blew up in my face,
I wanted to die.
If I died from carbon monoxide,
there'd be pictures of me.
If I fell off a high place,
I would become a spectacle.
So… I got on a fishing boat.
All right.
Woo-ryeong once told me
that she wanted to hang herself one night,
but she started to shave her legs first.
While shaving,
she realized how idiotic it all was,
so she changed her mind.
Not even a dog would wanna live my life.
I had no more desire to live.
But that man saved me.
I was a complete wreck.
I heard people's voices
and the ambulance on its way.
Even at that point,
all I wanted was to cover my face.
And that man there
took off his jacket and covered it for me.
For the first time in my life,
while everyone else wanted
to reveal my shame,
that man covered it.
PIECE OF JUNK
All right.
This banana milk is nothing.
That bigwig…
I went back to see him once
because I couldn't forget
what he did for me.
Oh God.
It makes no difference if he's buying pork
if it's a secret ballot.
People eat and still vote how they want.
I'm sure they'll want Ae-sun.
He lived as a man should.
Exactly as he should.
So, don't you not recognize me?
I won an award
for supporting actress yesterday.
I played a fisherman's wife.
I'm doing much better these days.
I thought there might be
some way to repay you.
Oh, no. It was nothing.
I couldn't accept a thing.
It was true then, and it's true now.
I can breathe again, thanks to you.
I want you to know
that nothing would make me happier
than the chance to repay you for that.
If there's anything, please let me know.
There's a lot I can do.
Who needs luck
when you have kindness?
It was only a reward
for the man with a heart of gold.
What if that man fights
with his wife over this?
She's bound to suspect something.
Why would you appear
at their restaurant out of the blue?
- She might know about it.
- I don't think she does.
Usually, men keep
that sort of thing to themselves.
It avoids conflict with the wife.
Well, you know what they say.
The way a man acts in life
is how he's remembered after he's gone.
Why did you look at me when you said that?
See? I told you she would come.
She came back a few years ago to thank me.
You must have said that a hundred times.
You just wanna show off, don't you?
Well, yeah, I saved a star.
I mean,
this is sort of impressive, isn't it?
You see how dirty Sang-gil is looking?
Just look at his shirt collar.
It's filthy.
You reap what you sow in life, don't you?
One man has faced down
all manner of storms and never budged.
Meanwhile, the other man
has spread himself thin all over town.
How can you compare them?
They're completely different animals.
THE SHARE OF SO-CALLED "GRAY DIVORCES"
INCREASED BY 18%
Those shoes are really nice.
They're very light.
The Maasai tribe wears them, apparently.
Where did you get these?
I have no idea.
I just wear what they buy me.
- They buy you shoes?
- Yeah, my wife and kids get them.
Come. You should eat before you go.
I could just eat at home, you know.
But why would you eat alone?
Just eat here.
My goodness, look at your belly!
That's what nothing
but ramyeon will do to you.
And for the love of God, get a haircut!
Are you avoiding it
because you're going bald?
Well, all right.
Thanks for inviting me.
Arigatou.
Hey, why can't you thank them
like a normal person?
Were you not planning
on fulfilling your duties as a father?
Just eat here, Dad.
BRIDE BU JEONG-SUK
DAUGHTER OF BU SANG-GIL AND PARK YEONG-RAN
You don't have to be so harsh.
It's not like he let us down in every way.
Right.
He did provide for you all, I suppose.
I meant the Cheol-yong thing.
You know Dad's the one who got him caught?
You pierce your child's heart
with a dagger.
No amount of money can pull it out.
You think you're the only one who cares?
I care a lot too.
I care more than you do.
Of course you work hard.
However, you have to choose
which cases you prioritize, don't you?
Can't you give me something more here?
You're the lead detective.
Money can make this go away, no?
Why doesn't he settle?
If he does that,
it's as good as pleading guilty.
If he really stole the thing,
he should face the consequences.
But why should a victim pay?
Besides, even if he settled
for such and such amount,
everyone will always
talk about him like a criminal.
Well, well, well.
You do care about your son-in-law.
I thought you couldn't stand him.
That's why I know he's innocent.
Eun-myeong's weak.
He doesn't have
what it takes to see it through.
You know, after my son
beat him up a couple of times,
he couldn't even bring himself
to ride the bus that stops by my house.
Oh.
Hello, sir.
Oh-seong, stay out of that gambling den.
This is your last warning.
Bow to him, you idiot.
- Show the man some respect!
- Ah, no, no. It's fine. It's fine.
All right, gimme that.
Oh God, that's heavy.
Wow. Okay.
Ah, this weighs a ton.
Velvet antler.
Goodness. Get that out of here.
What the hell am I supposed
to do with that? You keep it.
It's good for you.
I'm just looking out for your health.
Is that so terrible?
Take a look.
I think that Choi Bool-am
is the TV actor I respect the most.
He's always risking his life
to get the bad guy.
Catching a petty thief
can't be so hard, can it?
I'm Dodong-ri's Bu Sang-gil.
You'll never get a safer bribe.
I guarantee you.
Turns out, you're just as much
a father as any of us, Sang-gil.
I'll be damned.
Oh, please.
It's what a father would do for his child.
I was a village chief,
a captain, and a father.
And I have found
that being a father is the biggest loss.
- Now say "ah."
- I'm fine, really.
Come on, you look hungry.
Open up.
- Fine.
- Hey, don't bite the hand that feeds you.
When I listened to you refuse her
the money she needed to save her husband,
any sentiment I had left for you
disappeared from my heart forever.
You like giving newspaper interviews, huh?
Ah, hey, Sang-gil.
Just back up your car, and we can talk.
If you're such a supercop,
then why is Park Cheol-yong
still roaming the streets?
Well, what gives you the right
to park your car like this
in front of the police station?
Oh yeah!
You got your cut,
and now you're done with me, huh?
Is that what's going on?
Look, I promise you
I did the best I could.
- Is this guy Jean Valjean or what?
- Jean Valjean? What are you saying?
Why are you refusing
to finally hand him over to me?
It's the global era.
You have the Internet, everything,
so go find that lousy punk.
Sang-gil, are you drunk?
I've lost my wife and my fortune,
and I am losing my mind.
My life is spiraling out of control.
So if you don't want to be on the news
for the wrong reason,
either give me my money back with interest
or bring me Park Cheol-yong.
It is your choice, one or the other!
Interest?
Wow.
Dodong-ri's Bu Sang-gil
has sunk to a new low.
Dodong-ri's Bu Sang-gil.
To hell with that name! To hell with it!
How do you think they found Cheol-yong
through Joonggonara in the first place?
Isn't that funny?
Sang-gil and his little secrets.
- Always locking things up inside.
- What?
Like your ballroom dance class?
So when I snuck out to nightclubs,
I was just like you.
I had to. I couldn't breathe otherwise.
When I got home early in the morning,
I used to open the door slowly to see
if Dad was sleeping in the living room.
He didn't care enough about it
to stay awake for you.
Nuh-uh, he did.
One time, I saw him.
As soon as I opened the door,
he turned the TV off
and pretended he was asleep.
If you think about it…
Dad's actually a very timid man.
He yells a lot,
but if he thinks he'll lose,
he won't dare to put up a fight.
I think Dad was a little afraid
that, eventually,
everyone would leave him.
That man.
I can't stand when I see him.
I can't stand when I don't.
Eventually,
time makes all things
into watercolor paintings.
It blurs spite.
It softens people's hearts.
Bunch of ingrates.
I gave all of them my best,
but no one's ever
bought me something like that.
These days…
…I'm lucky to get a bag of rice.
Come to the restaurant tomorrow.
What, like I don't have plans?
There's a lot of places I could go.
Come on. Do it to help out your in-laws.
Once the show airs on TV,
it might get pretty busy.
I wanna be rich, too, one day.
Yeah?
Well, it's pretty nice
until people turn on you and take it.
In fact, I seriously doubt
you have what it takes to be rich.
You lack the mentality for it.
- Why can't you be nice for once?
- For once?
Are you coming by or not?
So you're saying
that you need me?
I'm saying it's your last chance.
To a building in the woods
that all had abandoned,
eight dwarves began gathering.
Hey, someone help me open this.
Here we go.
Eun-myeong, come help me.
And finally, at long last,
the dark forest
was filled with the ringing of bells.
"IF YOU CAN'T, JUST BACK DOWN.
WE'RE ALWAYS HERE FOR YOU."